# Bruno Moreira

Northwhich, UK
+44 0 7555-790209
brubom@gmail.com

## Software Development Manager

## **Summary**

I'm experienced in managing teams or working on solo projects with a high degree of complexity and delivering quality, using Scrum and XP. Strong track record of simplifying what is difficult and delivering results. I thrive in autonomous and creative environments, building a culture of fun, candor, and a bias for action.

Experience includes:

- \* PaaS / SaaS (.NET/C#, Java, JavaScript/NodeJS)
- \* Web sites
- \* Architecture: DevOps, SOA, API design, work on standardization, built several re-utilizable components and frameworks.
- \* Cloud-based, highly scalable architectures (Azure)
- \* Dev Tools: Jira (with Greenhopper), TeamCity, Jenkins, Checkmarx Sonar, Crucible, Bitbucket

### Work experience

#### Software Development Manager - AVP

Oct 2008 - Present

Barclays Investment Bank

Development leader for flexible teams and projects using Agile. Coordinating the efforts around internal and outsourced teams.

Interfacing with business key stakeholders to envision best solution design in the capital markets landscape. As an architect, I'm responsible for design architecture solutions, develop frameworks and patterns for development team.

#### **Team Leader Programmer Analyst**

May 2006 - Oct 2008

Bradesco

Worked as a team leader, coordinating the group that was responsible for intranet site development. Responsible for technology choice regarding solutions development. Software conception using C#, Visual Basic, Oracle, Sybase and SQL Server. Software maintenance for internal processes and bank products, such as cashing checks, paying employees and integrations with other banks.

#### **Programmer Analyst**

Aug 2004 - May 2006

SiaCorp

Programmer Analyst Participated in the modeling, documentation and development of the framework used in all company system, based on UML and Design Patterns. I was a team member of Siacorp's main product: iBasel, a tool that allows integrated management of operational risk, Development of workflow software solutions for analysis and lending to major banks such as Banco Pine, IBI Bank, Alfa Bank.

#### **Software Programmer**

May 2003 - Aug 2004

Success Tecnologia

Software Programmer Main developer of a commercial automation system Windows Forms in VB.Net Syngenta Crop Protection Ltd., with large volume of financial transactions. Development using C #components that were reused in various applications. Maintenance and development of Web systems developed with ASP.Net. Development and maintenance of applications in VB 6. 0 Novartis. Maintenance Web systems developed with ASP 3.0.

#### **Junior Software Programmer**

Feb 2001 - May 2003

Hypermarcas S/A

Junior Software Programmer I was responsible for development and maintenance for a set of applications: Call Center, Financial Management, Tax, Accounting and Medical Clinic. Development of applications directed to the Human Resources department.

#### **Education**

**BACHELORS** 2005 - 2008

Faculdade de Informática e Administração Paulista Bachelor's Degree , Computer Software Technology/Technician

#### **Certifications**

#### **Engineering Software as a Service**

Dec 2015 - Present

edX Berkeley University

MCAD: Microsoft .Net

Sep 2004 - Present

Microsoft

Developing XML Web Services and Server Components with Microsoft Visual C# .NET and the Microsoft .NET Framework

#### MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional

Dec 2003 - Present

Microsoft

Developing and Implementing Windows-based Applications with Microsoft Visual C#™ .NET and Microsoft Visual Studio .NET

#### Microsoft Sql Server

Dec 2004 - Present

Microsoft

Designing and Implementing Databases with Microsoft SQL Server